So, hello, everyone.
Thanks for coming to my talk.
Today, I'm going to be talking about Horde, specifically how it can be used by small teams,
and I'll show you ways we've reduced cost, and I'll show you what's actually involved
in deploying Horde.
So, before I get into things, just a little bit about me and the company I work for.
So, my name's Ash.
I'm a lead real-time developer at S1T2.
While my main focus is leading development on our Unreal-based experiences, I'm also responsible
for maintaining and developing the DevOps pipelines for these projects.
So, at S1T2, we mostly create immersive and interactive experiences, typically for institutions
like our galleries and museums.
And we use a lot of different technologies, but we mainly use Unreal Engine for these experiences.
So, at S1T2, we're a team that cares about fast iteration.
It's kind of due to the experimental nature of our work, as well as short timelines, and the need to adapt to changing requirements.
Our core team is also small, but we may expand our team with contractors or other partners depending on the work we take on.
And our team is also hybrid.
Some people work from the office or work from home, or maybe on-site in another country.
So, having remote access to our tools and infrastructure is important.
Actually, the picture in the bottom right is from the time we did a job in Dubai, and I got stuck there for like five months.
So, this talk is targeted towards small teams who are interested in Horde, but are unsure if it's the right thing for them.
As well as teams that don't have continuous integration set up yet.
To get the most out of this talk, it would be best to have some knowledge of Horde or similar tools, but it's okay if you don't.
Actually, how many people went to Jack's talk earlier on Horde?